Ajay Kumar Suneja 🗿 Featured

Anyone can fix a problem or develop a solution but my four years of experience in Java, Spring, Mysql, Front End Technologies have taught me beyond this, Don't just build a solution but Design the BEST solution..



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: NIIT Technologies Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Noida Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Noida, Gurgaon Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Core Java, MySQL, Javascript, HTML, JSP, Hibernate, Spring

Mvc,PHP,Codeigniter,JQuery,React.Js,Node.Js,Express,Spring Boot,Apache Camel,Mybatis,cvs,GIT,Docker,kubernetes

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

3+ years of experience in Software Development and IT Technical Support and also Part time Youtuber an experienced Java Developer with a strong interest in projects that require both conceptual and analytical thinking. Fully committed to Designing and Developing innovative web-based materials that users will love. Always eager to learn more tricks from anyone - regardless of the industry they are working in.

Work Experience

NIIT Technologies as Senior Software Engineer

Jan 2017 to Till Date

Software Trainee as 01/2017 - 07/2017,

Software Engineer 07/2019 - Present, Greater Noida, India

COFORGE Technologies is a leading global IT solutions organization. enabling its

clients to transform at the intersect of unparalleled domain expertise and

emerging technologies to achieve real-world business impact

Domain: Airline Cargo

Technology/Tools used: Java, JSP, Spring, Oracle, Ajax, Ant,

WebLogic, Linux, MQ Explorer, putty, Apache Camel, Eclipse Luna,

CVS, GIT, MySQL ,Linux, Front-end technologies (HTML, CSS 3,

jQuery, Ajax, JavaScript),

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

WWW.IAGCARGO.COM (07/2019 - Present)

IAG Cargo is the cargo handling division of International Airlines Group. IAG Cargo uses the freight capacity of its sister airlines' passenger fights, such as British Airways, and maintains three hubs located at Dublin Airport, Heathrow Airport

Fleet Business, British Airways & Iberia - IAG Cargo

07/2019 - Present)

Requirement analysis i.e. User story Analysis.

Developed/Fixed the Live incidents on IAGCARGO.com which help in

customer satisfaction and increased the IAG revenue.

1/22/2021

Module that I have worked on are EBooking, login,registration and user Management in IAGPortal.com.

Opportunity to work in "QM activities" like Code review and Code Check-in-

Check-out and so on.

Worked on development of one Java process to read messages from

different Queues using apache camel as business requirement.

Worked on development of one application WTPOS (Payment System) using

HTML, CSS, Spring, Hibernate as business requirement.

Worked on automated daily checks scripts using Linux and scheduled it through Cron Job.

Worked in both Delivery and Support.

Good experience in Release processes.

Client Site Experience

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

PHP & Codelgniter Experience (Freelancing) (2018 - Present)

Working with designers, Front End and project management staff to capture requirements for the functional elements of website projects. Also responsible for liaising with clients and ensuring that all work carried out complies with standards and guidelines.

Building PHP websites using PHP based frameworks like Codelgniter Rest API implement Using Codelgniter.

Developing compatible User Interface functionality using jQuery & other libraries. Developing web sites using MySQL, PHP.

Solid web development experience using OOP, PHP, AJAX, MySQL,

JavaScript, XML, HTML and CSS

My Work Repository - > Youtube/TechnicalSunejaji

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from GGIPU University, Delhi in 2014

PG: MCA (Computers) from GGIPU University, Delhi in 2017

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Core Java , Java 8, Spring MVC			
Hibernate & MyBatis			
REST API Using Spring BOOT, JSP, Servlet			
HTML, CSS, Boostrap			
React JS, ES6, JQuery, JavaScript			
Node & Express MYSQL & Mongo DB			
AJAX			
PHP & CodeIgniter			
CVS & GIT			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Projects

Project Title: IAGCARGO.com (02/2019 - Present)

Client: IA CARGO Iberia Airline
Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Feb 2020 - Mar 2020

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: 1)The platform provides users with dashboard functionality where they can manage their Bookings. 2)Module that I have worked on are EBooking, login,registration and user Management. 3)Developed/Fixed the Live

incidents on IAGCARGO.com which help in customer satisfaction and increased the IAG revenue

Project Title: Daily Checks Autmated Script

Client: IAG CARGO Iberia Airline Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Mar 2019 - Till Date

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: 1) Implemented automated daily checks scripts using Linux and scheduled it

through Cron Job , it runs daily and send it the server health details to business people. 2) Daily 30 Minutes Manual E7ort

Saved.

Project Title: WTPOS (Payment System)

Client: British Airways

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2018 - Dec 2019
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: 1) WTPOS is a complete Payment system that manages all Cargo shipments and

they process and stored them into that DB.

2) Technology used were Java ,Spring MVC , HTML , CSS , Bootstrap, JQUERY, Oracle.

Project Title: IAGCARGO Message Router

Client: British Airways

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: This Java Process receive the messages from One queue and send it to another Queue on basis of

flightmessages condition. Technology used were Java, Apache Camel, MyBatis.

Project Title: E-Commerce Platform

Client: NIIT Technologies

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2017 - Jun 2017

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: This Project allows user to buy and sell tangible goods, digital products or services online. Developing

compatible User Interface functionality using jQuery & other libraries. Developing web sites using MySQL, Codelgniter.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time